DARYNA TOKMACHOVA

• Software Development Engineer in Test (SDET)/QA Engineer •

Paris, France • +33609884323 • darynatok machova@gmail.com • Authorized to work without Sponsorship in France of the control of the control



ABOUT ME

Certified AGILE and ISTQB, test automation engineer with four-year IT project experience including 2-year SDET experience with manual, automation, database, API, and web and desktop application testing. Proven experience in SCRUM ceremonies in both Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Software Test Life Cycle (STLC), building and maintaining existing BDD/TDD/Hybrid testing frameworks. Ability to create automation frameworks from scratch using Java, JUnit annotations, TestNG, Maven, Jenkins, Postman, Oracle SQL Developer, Cucumber, RestAssured Library, JDBC, Selenium WebDriver, and tools. I have good organization and communications skills and get things done approach. I really enjoy working in a collaborative and international environment. I speak fluently English, French, Russian, and Ukrainian and have a good understanding of German

SKILLS

Selenium WebDriver, JUnit, Postman, Rest Assured API, Karate DSL, SQL Developer, Cucumber, TestNG, Page Object Model (POM), IntelliJ, Eclipse, JDBC, Oracle Database, Apache POI, Maven, Jenkins, GitHub, Git, Agile (Scrum), Waterfall, Jira, Jira X-Ray, basic knowledge of mobile testing, npm, MongoDB, VS Code

Languages: Java, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), SQL, JavaScript, Python(basics), Gherkin, HTML

People skills: teamwork, detail-oriented, presentation, analytical & organization skills, creativity, thinking outside the box

EXPERIENCE

Capgemini for McDonald's | May 2021 - December 2020 - Test Automation Engineer

- Run functional, automation, smoke, positive and negative tests and regression suite for **web and desktop** applications
- Install and configure test tools on laboratory equipment
- Create test scripts using **JavaScript**, Opentest, **MongoDB** and **npm** tested on restaurant kiosks and points of sales(POS).
- Increase regression test automation coverage and review manual test cases
- Maintain existing scripts based on new software updates on equipment.
- Adapt changes according to projects and specific client needs

Environment: test automation, web and desktop user interface tests, regression testing

FleetApps | July 2020 - April 2021. - Test Automation Engineer

- Execute functional, automation, smoke, regression, positive and negative testing for web-applications
- Design test scenarios and test cases based on acceptance criteria in behavior-driven development Cucumber Page Object Model framework using Gherkin, Java, Selenium WebDriver, and JUnit annotations
- Execute test scripts using Java and Selenium WebDriver in version control projects in **IntelliJ**, creating pull requests in GitHub and **resolving conflicts** if requested by the team lead
- Implement Java OOP and data-driven tests daily with test parameterization methods using **Cucumber**Scenario Outline
- Create emails reports with smoke test execution results and analyze them in Jenkins and create **bug tickets** in JIRA if necessary

- Create extent/HTML/Cucumber JSON reports for failed test cases for Product Owner
- Participate in two-week sprints and in **SCRUM** ceremonies: Sprint Planning, Daily Standup, Sprint Review, Demo, and Retrospective meetings
- Ensure API testing manually Postman or thanks to automation using REST Assured library with Java and GET, POST, PUT, and DELETE methods in BDD frameworks like Karate or Cucumber with Maven dependencies for APACHE POI
- Perform database testing using SQL language and Java Database Connectivity (**JDBC**) enabled by Oracle Maven dependencies and configuration of AWS EC2
- Be in constant communication with the IT team, teammates, and Product Owner via Slack, Zoom, and Asana

Environment: Continuous Integration - Continuous Testing (CI/CT), test automation, UI & backend testing, POM Cucumber

OpenlyCRM | March 2020 - June 2020 - Test Automation Engineer

- Built BDD UI testing framework from scratch in Java using Maven, Selenium WebDriver, Cucumber, Gherkin, and tools
- Wrote test execution data- or behavior-driven scripts in Java for UI testing with Selenium WebDriver
- Was responsible for increasing test automation coverage by using Java, **Cucumber POM** framework built with Maven dependencies (JUnit, Selenium WebDriver)
- Reduced regression suite thanks to data-driven tests with Cucumber Scenario Outlines
- Ensured Backend testing with database automation testing by building **JDBC** and performing verification of SQL queries with API Web Services testing using **REST Assured Library**
- Performed manual and automation API testing using REST Assured Library and Postman

Environment: Continuous Integration - Continuous Testing (CI/CT), test automation, UI & backend testing, API testing, manual testing

CNH (Fiat) (France) - Oct 2019 - Sept 2020 - Pricing Analyst (work-study contract)

- Used IBM Data Management tools for pricing analyses for Europe
- Monitoring and calculated pricing KPIs
- Conducted daily pricing reviews with product managers

Eaton (France) - Sept 2018 - Sept 2019 - Pricing Assistant(work-study contract)

- · Had a role of a Data Quality Officer: establishing a new set of rules for regular data checkups
- Maintained communication with European and American teams over implementing a new machine-learning pricing tool
- Conducted data output audits and elaborated pricing logic rules translated in SQL

Goldschmidt Thermit (Germany) - April- August 2018 - Product Manager Assistant (internship)

- · Maintained communication with subsidiaries in France and Poland over digitization project
- · Assisted Product Manager in the SaaS launch project with marketing research and market entry strategies
- Created documentation for the project in both French and English

EDUCATION

- Cybertek School (VA, USA) Boot Camp Software Development Engineering in Test with apprenticeship programs
- 2020 SKEMA Business School (Paris, France) Master's degree in Marketing Data and E-commerce. Graduated among top 4 students (3%)